Austin Wiley

Email: austin@spangalangbrewery.com | Phone: 303-905-7293 | Littleton, CO 80120

Github: https://github.com/AustinWiley

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-wiley-86868416b/
Portfolio: https://austinwiley.github.io/Austin-Portfolio/

Web Developer and Entrepreneur. Experienced in creative problem solving, collaboration, team management, training and organization, product/process development and supply relations. Enjoys working in teams, whether that be in a position of leadership or taking instruction. A lifelong learner using the work of Web Development to cultivate an environment of continuing education that align with current and future skills, experience and goals. Always looking forward to new challenges that promote growth.

Technical Skills: Javascript, CSS, and HTML. Experience with the following technologies and frameworks: JQuery, Node.js, Google Firebase, Twitter Bootstrap, Moment.js, Google Fonts, & Font Awesome.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Camp With Confidence Github / Live

- Web app that searches National Park API for camp sites, takes in your camp site selection and returns weather forecast from Open Weather API for that location and uses Leaflet map API to show you a map location of the camp site.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, JQuery, Css, Google Firebase, Font Awesome, Twitter Bootstrap, Leaflet maps.

Train Scheduler Github / Live

- One page Web App that allows you to create a Train Schedule with form input validation and persistent data using Google Firebase.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Google Firebase and Moment.js.

Beer Trivia Web App Github / Live

- One page Web App trivia game. This game relies heavily on JQuery DOM manipulation for starting and finishing the game and Moment.js for timing the game play.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS and Moment.js.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Spangalang Brewery, Denver, CO

February 2015 - Present

Owner

Co-Founded and Operated a successful craft brewery. Created world class beer that won GABF Gold medal and World Beer Cup awards. Managed staff and daily operations of of the business including head of Human Resources. As Co-Founder researched local and federal laws and regulations, obtained necessary permits and licenses and managed cross-functional communication between equipment Engineers, Architects, Contractors, and local government.

Denver Beer Co, Denver, CO

February 2014 - February 2015

Head Brewer

Managed Brew house operations and staff during a time of major growth. Developed and Brewed beer that became a major part of the companies portfolio as well as won nationally recognized awards.

Great Divide Brewing Co, Denver, CO

April 2007 - February 2014

Lead Brewer

Research and recipe development for award winning beer, team management, staff training, equipment accusation and creating production processes and standards playing a major role in helping the company increase production during a time of rapid growth.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js.

Brewing Science Institute, Woodland Park, CO

Certificate in cell counting and lab operations.